Welcome back.
I'm excited to help you learn full stack application development with React and Spring Boot.
And I'm sure you are as excited as I am! In this step,
let's discuss the high level architecture of the application
we are going to build in this course.
Let's start with understanding the basic functionality of the application, that we are going to build.
We are going to build a Todo Management Application.
Everybody has things that they want to do,
they want to learn.
You want to learn how to develop a full stack application with React! You can manage all of them in
this Todo management application.
You can add a todo,
You can delete a todo, and also update a todo as well.
Other than that, it will also have the authentication features, typically the log in and log out capabilities.
Let's now shift our attention to what the architecture of the application that we are going to develop
What we are going to develop is a full stack application.
When we talk about a full stack application, we are talking about a front-end application, which is talking
to a backend API, or  a REST web service.
We are going to use React to build the front end part. React is a front end View framework,
and it makes it easy to develop front end applications.
We would be using modern Javascript. If you're not familiar with modern Javascript,
that's not a problem at all.
We would make sure that you are sufficiently introduced to the modern Javascript concepts, before we
would use them in the codes. To build the RESTful API or RESTful services in the back end,
we'll be using Spring Boot framework.
We'll be using Java as the programming language.  Spring Boot is the number one Java framework to build
RESTful APIs and micro services. We will create multiple RESTful services for authentication, as well as
todo management.As far as authentication is concerned,
we will start with basic authentication, and also discuss about how you can use JWTs, or JSON  web
tokens for authentication.
We will use the spring security framework to build authentication around all the API, that we are going
to build. Before we move on to the next step,
let's discuss an important question.
You're talking about building full stack applications.
Why should you really build a full stack application?
Why should you create a separate back end, and a  separate front end.
And there is a lot of complexity associated with this:
You need multiple languages,
You need multiple frameworks like Spring Boot, React.,
You need to learn all of that.
Why should you really do that?
The answer to that question is that you would want to create a flexible architecture, an architecture
which can be extended to meet your future needs.
Let's imagine you want to develop a native mobile application in future, let's say an iPhone app or an
Android application.
Maybe you'd want to connect the application to Internet of Things devices IoT devices. In such kind
of situations,
We can reuse the exposed backend API.  The full stack application, with the separate back end API or
the RESTful API, will give us more options to extend our architecture, and create different applications
for different devices.
In this quick step,  we looked at the architecture of the application that we are going to create.
We create a React front-end app talking to a RESTful back end API, build on top of Spring Boot.
We also discussed why we build full stack applications.
I'll see you in the next step.
Until then, bye bye!