Welcome back.
In the first few steps of this course, for almost an hour and half, we will be focusing on the React application.
You would want to understand the basic concepts of React.
Most importantly, how do you build components with React? In the step,
let's start with creating a simple React application.
How do you create a React application?
create-react-app
If you do a Google search for create-react-app. you'd land up on the create-react-app homepage.
This is a GitHub repository, and you'd see that create-react-app
is used to set up a modern web application by running one command.
Basically what it helps us to do, is to create a simple React application just by running one simple
command.
What is that command?
Just scroll down a little and here it is.
So if you execute a command which is similar to this create-react-app, it would create the basic setup of
a React application.
Actually it would create an application which is good enough to take to production, as is.  To be able
to use the create-react-app,
We would need node and npm.
Let us launch up our terminal command prompt.
If you're on Mac it's terminal.
If you are on any other operating system like windows for example you have to launch up the command
prompt.
Just type in terminal, and you'd be able to launch up the terminal window. If you're on Windows you might
want to launch up the command prompt in this way.
Press Control-Esc.
Launch up the start menu, type in çmd, click the command prompt and it will open up for you now.
Once your terminal or command prompt is opened, all that you need to do is type in node
--version.
So important to note there are two hyphens in here,  right? So it's node --version
So once you have a version which is greater than 10 that's cool.
You can also type in npm -version to find out which npm version you have.
If either node doesn't work for you, or the npm doesn't work for you, make sure that you check the installation
guide which we looked at earlier in the course.
The command we need to execute to create the React app is in npx create-react-app and
the name of your application.
So the way we can do that is npx create-react-app ,  the name of the application
I would want to use is todo-app.
But before that what we need to do we need to move to the folder where we would want to create this
particular application, right!
So let's cd  to the folder where you'd want to create that application.
I want to create it in this folder so I am doing a cd to in28minutes/git/full-stack-with
react-and-spring-boot/ frontend. And over here, I can execute the npx command -  npx create-react-app
todo-app. Once you execute this command, you'll see that this would take a little bit of time
because this would create the project and also build it.
So this project is created.
Now it's trying to build it.
It's trying to install a few dependencies. React,  React DOM and React Script, and also their transitive
dependencies.
So only things that React DOM needs to work. All the things that React needs to work, and all the things
that React Scripts need to work.
If you have a problem at this stage and if you are not seeing a project being built like this, or if
you get a permissions error, then one of the things you can do is you can try and launch up the command
prompt as an administrator.
So all here when you press control-Esc, launch up the command prompt and open up command prompt. All
Over here, if you right click on the command prompt you ca do Run As  Administrator. If you are on Mac. or
On Linux you can try Sudo.
So instead of trying npx create-react-app todo-app,  you can try doing sudo npx create-react-app
todo- app.
The other useful thing to do is to google for create-react-app troubleshooting.
This would take you to a github page with Facebook , to  get a broader view.
So once you click that you can see a few other things you can do right now. You see that the installation
is going on right now.
It might take a few minutes especially if you're running it for the first time. And after the whole thing
is done, you'd see that it lists the different commands that you can run.
The great thing is now if the entire application is set up,  so if you open up that specific folder. So
if I do present working directory pwd,  this is a folder where the project is created.
So if I go to frontend,  there is a todo-app folder where all the content is created.
The entire project is created in this specific folder.
There are a number of commands which create-react-app enables. You can do npm test to run the unit
test which are present in the project.
You can do npm run build to create a production deployable, where we write JavaScript code in modern
javascript applications.
We would create hundreds of JavaScript files and it not efficient in production to have hundreds of
JavaScript files.
So what npm run build does,  is it merges everything into a compressed set of JavaScript files, which you
can then use for production.
All these features are actually built in into the application which is created by using the create-react-
app.
The thing that you'd want to do now is to launch up the application.
Let us do that right now. The way you can launch up the application is by saying npm start.
So it's the command which is present in here.
npm start.  So when you press npm start,
there there's an error.
It says I cannot find a package.json File.
Okay cool.
Let me check the present working directory and they are in linux,  or they are in Windows.
You'd see that I'm still in the frontend folder. To be able to run the npm start command,
I would need to  cd into the todo-app folder.
So let's do a cd to the todo-app folder, and now let's go ahead and run npm start.
And this would kick off the launch of the project.
So you can see that the project starts up and launches it in the browser as well.
This might take a little while.
The pages still loading and you'd see that it's showing the URLs on the console.
So if you'd want to launched it in Chrome, you can take this URL and launch it in Chrome.
Most probably it would have been automatically launched up in your default browser.
What if it has not launched in your default browser, then you can take this URL and execute it preferably
in Chrome, because that's the browser we be using for the most part in this course.
Congratulations!
In the step, we created a React application. All that we needed to do was to execute a command npx
create-react-app and give the name of the application.
The application was created and after that, we just needed to do npm start to launch that application
up, and we were able to see the application in the browser.
Right now we don't really understand what's happening in the background.
And that's what we would be looking at in the subsequent steps. Until the next step, bye bye!