Welcome back.
In the previous step, we launched up our first React app in the browser.
Isn't that cool!
Let's take a step further.
In this particular step let's try and make a small change to this React app, and see how to get that
change rendered in the browser.
What we do is we will use Visual Studio Code as the IDE. Let's now launch the application in Visual
Studio Code, during the installation guide section of this course.
You have already installed Visual Studio code. With the launch of Visual Studio Code,
This is what you would see.
You'd see that we have actually worked on a number of projects recently to make sure that this code
is perfect.
The other things that you see in here are help and the learned stuff.
I would recommend you to spend some time with the learn stuff, to familiarize yourself with the Visual
Studio Code IDE.
There are a lot of things that you can customize with these IDE, but now would want to open up our
project in Visual Studio Code.There are two ways you can do that: one is open folder.
So once you click open folder, you can navigate to the folder where your project is, and you can open
it.
The other option is drag and drop.
So I've created todo-app in this specific folder.
I can drag it and directly drop it in here.
Once you drag the folder in there,  Visual Studio Code would open up that particular project.
You can see the different folders from that specific project, and other files which are present in there
as well.
Now let's pick up one of these files package.json.  Let's not worry about what the content of this
file is, for now.
Now I would want to see this in full screen.
How can I do that? The way you can do that is by toggling the explorer bar or by using a control-B, or
a command-B.
This is very important because whenever you are working on a file you would want to actually work in
fullscreen mode, and that's the reason why you wanted to cover it up.
The first thing that we teach as part of our IDE is : Control B or command B is the shortcut to actually
maximize this window.
The other thing you can do is also to toggle the explorer back.
So what are you are testing in here is called the Explorer bar, where you can actually navigate through all
the files folders and everything related to your project.
There are a lot of other features which are present in Visual Studio code.
You can search for a file.
You can look at your source control, I mean if we actually put it in a Git repository or something.
You can actually check which files are committed,  which are not -  all that stuff in total control in here.
You can debug, as well as there are a number of extensions you can add on top of Visual Studio code. You
can check all that stuff on the left hand side bar, which is present in here. For now,
let's not worry about all of them. Let's focus on actually learning React. Now that we have the application
opened up in the IDE, let's make a couple of changes. I'll open up the source folder and the public folder.
The public folder has something called index.html, which is actually the page which is loaded
up when we type in localhost:3000 in the browser.
This index.html contains a title element. You can see that the title is React App in here.
Let's make a small change.
Let's call this Todo Application,  or even further,
You can call this My Todo Application.
You'd see that the changes immediately reflected on the browser.
Right.
So the title comes from index.html.
That's what we understood right.
The App.js is where all the rest of the content of the page is coming from.
So inside the source there is a file called App.js,  and this contains all the stuff you are seeing in
here.
So you can see that there is a logo which is being put and it says.
Edit src/App.js. I'll save it and I will do a reload.
So what I'll do is now I'll remove all this content which is present in here.
Let's remove the header which is present in the here and let's save it.
Let's see if the change reflects. Yep, the change reflects immediately. To make it easy.
I'll say My Hello
World, and save it.
Now you'd see that the change is reflected in the browser.
Now what?
What's the magic that is happening here, is that the change in index.html is getting reflected, App.js
is getting reflected! All that magic is happening because of the create-react-app.
When we build the application with create-react-app and we started using npm start, automatically
It would keep scanning your code for changes.
So as soon as a code change happens, it is automatically built and it is rendered to the browser.
In this step we imported the project into our IDE.
Visual Studio Code,  and we also made a couple of modifications to it, and saw that they were
immediately rendered in the browser.
In the next step we would start looking at the individual folders, and the different files which are
present in here.
I'll see you in the next step. Until then, bye-bye!